Guide to the Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM) Vertical Files RISM.VF.1
New York University Archives
- Caribbean Area
  - Caribbean Area: Tariff (Box 7)
    - A Guide for Use of Exporters and Importers, 1971; RISM 20461; Caribbean Free Trade Association. Commonwealth Caribbean Regional Secretariat. Trade and Integration Division; 24 pages (Box 7)
      Tariff.; Caribbean Area.
    - The Brussels Tariff Nomenclature: A Short Commentary on the Brussels Tariff Classification System, 1971; RISM 20462; Caribbean Free Trade Association. Commonwealth Caribbean Regional Secretariat. Trade and Integration Division; 30 pages (Box 7)
  - Caribbean Area: Taxation (Box 7)
    - Taxation and Investment Incentives in the Caribbean Region, 1976; RISM 20463; 22 pages (Box 7)
      Taxation.; Caribbean Area.
    - St. Lucia to be Removed from OECD International Blacklist, 2002; RISM 26913; 1 page; 1p. (Box 7)
      Caribbean Area.; Taxation.
  - Caribbean Area: Teachers, Training of (Box 7)
    - The Role of the Institute of Education, 1964; RISM 11859; Springer, Hugh W. (Box 7)
      Caribbean Area.; Teachers
    - The School Teacher in His Role as Leader in West Indian and African Societies, 1960; RISM 20464; Collins, Sidney; p. 315-324. (Box 7)
    - External Teacher Training: A Study of the Problem of the Pupil-Teacher and Probationary Teacher Systems in the British Caribbean, 1955; RISM 20466; Griffiths, V. L. (Vincent Llewellyn); 33 pages (Box 7)
    - Recruitment and Training of Training College Staff, 1964; RISM 20467; 23 pages (Box 7)
    - UWIDITE: University of the West Indies; Distance Teaching Experiment Handbook for Students, 1990-1991; RISM 24703; University of the West Indies (Mona, Jamaica). Department of Educational Studies. Faculty of Education; 23 pages (Box 7)
    - Education Foundations Programme for Teachers' Colleges in the Eastern Caribbean, undated; RISM 24771; Grenada Teachers' College; 35 pages (Box 7)
    - In-Service Teacher Education: A New Kind of Teacher for the New Society, 1980; RISM 20468; 18 pages (Box 7)
  - Caribbean Area: Technology (Box 7)
    - White Magic: The Caribbean and Modern Technology, 1978; RISM 20469; Girvan, Norman, 1941-; p. 153-166. (Box 7)
      Technology.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Textile Industry and Trade (Box 7)
    - Caribbean Basin Initiative: Special Access Textile Program, 1988; RISM 20470; United States. Department of State. Bureau of Public Affairs; 2 pages (Box 7)
      Textile industry.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Tourism (Box 7)
    - Tips for Travelers to the Caribbean, 1993; RISM 20471; United States. Bureau of Consular Affairs; 20 pages (Box 7)
      Tourism.; Caribbean Area.
    - Westindien als Fremdenverkehrsgebiet, 1963; RISM 20472; Blume, Helmut; p. 47-72. (Box 7)
    - Industry and Tourism, 1981; RISM 20473; Caribbean Development Bank; 24 pages (Box 7)
    - What Follows the Caribbean's "Topsy" Tourism?, 1972; RISM 20475; Linton, Neville; p. 5-9. (Box 7)
    - Tourism and Caribbean Development, 1983; RISM 20476; Conway, Dennis, 1941-; 12 pages (Box 7)
    - An Alternative to the Mass Market Philosophy for Micro Caribbean States, 1984; RISM 20477; Miller, Luther G.; 24 pages (Box 7)
    - Organization of Eastern Caribbean States: World Bank Approves $20.9 Million to Support Recovery of Caribbean Tourism, 2002; RISM 26919; 1 page; 1p. (Box 7)
      Caribbean Area.; Tourism.
    - In the Compound of Their Skins: Island Identities and the Global Market, 2000; RISM 27395; Titley, Gavan; 8 pages; 8.0 (Box 7)
    - Caribbean Tourism Organization; Intra-Regional Travel Market Study, 1999; RISM 27484; Caribbean Tourism Organization; 12 pages; 12.0 (Box 7)
  - Caribbean Area: Tourism, Bibliography (Box 7)
    - Tourism: A List of References to the Literature Held in the Library, University of the West Indies, 1981; RISM 20478; University of the West Indies (Saint Augustine, Trinidad and Tobago). Alma Jordan Library; 12 pages (Box 7)
      Bibliography.; Caribbean Area.; Tourism.
  - Caribbean Area: Trade Unions (Box 7)
    - Dynamics in the Rise of Labour Organizations and Early Craft Unions in the British Caribbean, 1897-1914, 1984; RISM 20479; Basdeo, Sahadeo; 15 pages (Box 7)
      Caribbean Area.; Labor unions
  - Caribbean Area: Transportation (Box 7)
    - Caribbean Development Bank; Transportation, 1981; RISM 20483; Caribbean Development Bank; 16 pages (Box 7)
      Transportation.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Tropical Plants (Box 7)
    - Lexique sur la Flore Caraibe: A Lexical Guide to the Caribbean Flora, 1984; RISM 20484; Louis, Harry; 55 pages (Box 7)
      Caribbean Area.; Tropical plants.
  - Caribbean Area: Turtles (Box 7)
    - Sea Turtles of the Caribbean, 1972; RISM 20485; Hanif, Mahamad; 5 pages (Box 7)
      Turtles.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Unemployed (Box 8)
    - Overpopulation and Underemployment in the West Indies, 1960; RISM 20486; Harewood, Jack; 32 pages; p. 1-32. (Box 8)
      Caribbean Area.; Unemployed
    - Unemployment and the Unemployed in the Caribbean: New Directions for Sociological Research, 1977; RISM 23954; Brathwaite, Farley; p. 48-73. (Box 8)
      Unemployed; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Universities and Colleges (Box 8)
    - University College of the West Indies, Mona, Jamaica, West Indies, undated; RISM 20488; 2 pages; brochure. (Box 8)
      Caribbean Area.; Universities and colleges.
    - University College of the West Indies; Address by the Principal on the Occasion of the Matriculation of New Students at Mona, 1960; RISM 20489; Lewis, W. Arthur (William Arthur), 1915-1991; unpaged (Box 8)
    - The Proposed British West Indian University, 1946; RISM 20491; Williams, Eric Eustace, 1911-1981; 4 pages (Box 8)
    - The Idea of a British West Indian University, 1945; RISM 20492; Williams, Eric Eustace, 1911-1981; p. 182-191. (Box 8)
      Universities and colleges.; Caribbean Area.
    - The West Indies; Article on the Extra-Mural Department of the University of the West Indies, undated; RISM 20493; Nettleford, Rex M., 1933-2010; p. 181-211. (Box 8)
    - Address at the Graduation Exercises at the University of the West Indies; With the Odds Against Us, 1969; RISM 20494; Benítez, Jaime, 1908-2001; 18 pages (Box 8)
    - University of the West Indies; Statement of Principles for the Guidance of Staff, undated; RISM 20495; University of the West Indies; 5 pages (Box 8)
    - University of the West Indies: Department of Extra-Mural Studies, undated; RISM 20496; 7 pages (Box 8)
    - The University College of the West Indies, ca. 1953; RISM 20497; Taylor, T. W. J. (Thomas Weston Johns), 1895-; p. 3-16 (Box 8)
    - The University in the Caribbean in the Late 20th Century, 1980-1999, 1974; RISM 20498; Williams, Eric Eustace, 1911-1981; 33 pages (Box 8)
    - The University and the People: Two Addresses at the II Caribbean Conference of Intellectual Workers, 1984; RISM 20499; Pereira, J. R. (Joseph R.); 33 pages (Box 8)
    - University College of the West Indies; Memorandum, 1957; RISM 19057; University College of the West Indies; 4 pages (Box 8)
    - Les Universites et L'Enseignement des Sciences Sociales dans les pays de L'Ameique Centrale et des Antilles, 1955; RISM 23430; Clemens, Ren; p. 3-29. (Box 8)
  - Caribbean Area: Urbanization (Box 8)
    - Urbanization in the Caribbean, 1974; RISM 20500; Clarke, Colin G.; p. 223-232. (Box 8)
      Urbanization.; Caribbean Area.
    - Problems of Employment and Housing in West Indian Towns, 1975; RISM 20501; Clarke, Colin G.; p. 5-15. (Box 8)
    - The Commonwealth Caribbean, 1975; RISM 20503; Clarke, Colin G.; p. 341-351. (Box 8)
  - Caribbean Area: Vocational Education (Box 8)
    - OECS/CDB Technical and Vocational Education Pilot Programme; Pre-Vocational Curriculum Development Workshop for Related Subject Areas, 1990; RISM 24745; O.E.C.S. (Organization); 2 pages (Box 8)
      Vocational education.; Caribbean Area.
    - CDB/OECS Technical and Vocational Education Project; The Pre-Vocational Curriculum Seminar for Country Curriculum Coordinators, 1989; RISM 24776; Caribbean Development Bank. OECS Technical and Vocational Education Project; various paging. (Box 8)
      Caribbean Area.; Vocational education.
    - Workshop on Role of Pre-Vocational Education and Training (PET); Presentation on 'Curriculum Content', 1988; RISM 24744; Sabaroche, Herbert F.; 24 pages (Box 8)
      Vocational education.; Grenada.
  - Caribbean Area: Water Supply (Box 8)
    - Water and Sewerage, 1981; RISM 20504; Caribbean Development Bank; 9 pages (Box 8)
      Water-supply.; Caribbean Area.
    - Bio-Technology in the Management of Reservoirs in the Caribbean, 1982; RISM 20505; Bacchus, Zinul; 7 pages (Box 8)
  - Caribbean Area: Windmills (Box 8)
    - Brace Research Institute; Visit to Antigua, St. Kitts, Nevis and Barbados, 1970; RISM 20506; Lake, E. B.; 5 pages (Box 8)
      Caribbean Area.; Windmills.
  - Caribbean Area: Women (Box 8)
    - Women, Adult Education and Literacy: A Caribbean Perspective, 1985; RISM 17966; Ellis, Patricia; 5 pages (Box 8)
      Women.; Caribbean Area.
    - Mini Courses in Social Studies: An Introduction to Women's Studies Prepared for Social Studies Education, 1981; RISM 18925; Ellis, Patricia; 10 pages (Box 8)
      Caribbean Area.; Women.
    - Response - United Methodist Women; Special Issue on the Caribbean, 1977; RISM 20509; 51 pages (Box 8)
    - Women in Caribbean Development: UNICA Meeting, 1982; RISM 20510; Association of Caribbean Universities and Research Institutes; 10 pages (Box 8)
    - Women in Caribbean Society: The Trade Union Movement, 1988; RISM 20511; Thomas, Vereen; 4 pages (Box 8)
    - Planning for Women in Rural Development: Extract; Methodological Overview, ca. 1986; RISM 20512; Staudt, Kathleen A.; p. 4-14, 104-109. (Box 8)
    - Institutions and Programmes for the Decade, 1985; RISM 20513; Antrobus, Peggy; 4 pages (Box 8)
    - The Status of Male/Female Relationships, 1985; RISM 20514; Shorey-Bryan, Norma; 4 pages (Box 8)
    - Women and the Process of Social Change, 1985; RISM 20515; Manley, Beverly; 4 pages (Box 8)
    - The Caribbean: Crisis and Challenges, 1988; RISM 20516; Nettleford, Rex M., 1933-2010; 7 pages (Box 8)
    - Profiles of Women in Contemporary Caribbean History, ca. 1982; RISM 20517; Haniff, Nesha Z., 1948-; 11 pages (Box 8)
    - Women in Social Development: Health and Education in the Commonwealth Caribbean over the Decade for Women, 1985; RISM 20518; Drayton, Kathleen; 10 pages (Box 8)
    - The Impact of Industrialization on Women: A Caribbean Case, 1980; RISM 20520; Abraham-Van der Mark, Eva; p. 374-386. (Box 8)
    - Studying the History of Women, 1986; RISM 20521; Brereton, Bridget, 1946-; 5 pages (Box 8)
    - From Research to Social Action: The Experience of Other Third World Countries, 1982; RISM 23187; Jain, Devaki, 1933-; 7 pages (Box 8)
    - About CAFRA; Caribbean Association for Feminist Research and Action, 2001; RISM 27255; Caribbean Association for Feminist Research and Action (CAFRA); 10 pages; 10.0 (Box 8)
  - Caribbean Area: Women, Employment (Box 8)
    - Work in the Lives of Caribbean Women, 1982; RISM 20523; Massiah, Joycelin; 26 pages (Box 8)
      Caribbean Area.; Women.; Employment.
    - Women and Industry, 1985; RISM 20524; Durant-Gonzalez, Victoria; 3 pages (Box 8)
      Employment.; Caribbean Area.; Women.
    - Employment of Women Workers in the Caribbean, 1979; RISM 20525; Antrobus, Peggy; 4 pages (Box 8)
      Women.; Employment.; Caribbean Area.
    - Women and Entrepreneurship, 1985; RISM 23245; Bell, Jeanette; 3 pages (Box 8)
    - Women as Productive Workers, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Caribbean Area: Women in Literature (Box 8)
    - The Construction of the Imaginary Homeland: Migrating Women in Novels by Caribbean Women Writers, 2000; RISM 25909; Rodríguez, María Cristina; p. 307-320. (Box 8)
      Caribbean Area.; Women in literature.
    - Cultural Identity, 'Resistance', & Women's Postcolonial Writing from the African-Caribbean/British Borderlands: Joan Riley's 'The Unbelonging', 2000; RISM 27397; Perry, Barbara S.; 7 pages; 7.0 (Box 8)
    - The Corporeal and the Sensual in Two Novels by Shani Mootoo and Julia Alvarez, 2002; RISM 27410; Brüning, Angela; 19 pages; 19.0 (Box 8)
  - Caribbean Area: Women in Politics (Box 8)
    - Caribbean Women for Democracy, 1985; RISM 20528; Gregory, Marie; 44 pages (Box 8)
      Caribbean Area.; Women in politics.
    - Caribbean Women and the Political Process, 1985; RISM 20527; Anderson, Beverley; 5 pages (Box 8)
  - Caribbean Area: Women Slaves (Box 8)
    - Dis-Ordering the World in the 18th Century: The Duplicity of Connoisseurship; Masking the Culture of Slavery, or, The Voyage of Sable Venus: Connoisseurship and the Trivializing of Slavery, 2002; RISM 27414; McCrea, Rosalie Smith; 19 pages; 19.0 (Box 8)
      Caribbean Area.; Women slaves.
  - Caribbean Area: Youth (Box 8)
    - Democracy and Youth in the Caribbean; Report of a Seminar, August 1987; RISM 20529; Bustamante Institute of Public and International Affairs; 32 pages (Box 8)
      Caribbean Area.; Youth.
    - Youth in the Caribbean: Reaching for Maturity, 1961; RISM 20532; Close, Kathryn; p. 123-129. (Box 8)
    - Youth, Voluntary Associations, and Community Development in the Eastern Caribbean, 1982; RISM 23950; Brana-Shute, Gary; 41 pages (Box 8)
      Youth.; Caribbean Area.
    - The Challenge of Youth Unemployment in the Caribbean: The Role of Youth Employment Training Programmes, 1988; RISM 27184; International Labour Organization. Caribbean Office; various paging (Box 8)
    - The Adolescent in the Changing Caribbean: Preliminary Programme, 1961; RISM 24869; 4 pages (Box 8)
- Carriacou Island (Box 8)
  - Carriacou Island (Box 8)
    - The Over-Development of Carriacou, 1975; RISM 17551; Richardson, Bonham C., 1939-; p. 390-399. (Box 8)
      Carriacou Island (Grenada).
    - Grenada; Report of the Carriacou District for the Year 1964, 1965; RISM 17554; 7 pages (Box 8)
    - Carriacou Past and Present, 1966; RISM 17555; p. 10-12. (Box 8)
    - Carriacou: An Old World in the New, 1960; RISM 20537; Kingsbury, Robert C.; p. 399-409 (Box 8)
    - Carriacou: Gem of the Grenadines, 1988; 10 pages (Box 8)
  - Carriacou Island: Art (Box 8)
    - People in Paradise: Canute Caliste, 1991; RISM 16822; Fine, Brenda; p. 82, 110-112. (Box 8)
      Carriacou Island (Grenada).; Art.
  - Carriacou Island: Emigration and Immigration (Box 8)
    - Labor Migrants from the Island of Carriacou: Workers on the Margins of the Developed World, 1974; RISM 17550; Richardson, Bonham C., 1939-; p. 149-152. (Box 8)
      Emigration and immigration.; Carriacou Island (Grenada).
    - West Indian Migration: Host Countries and Differential Change in the Sending Culture, 1972; RISM 17552; Hill, Donald R., 1939-; 6 pages (Box 8)
      Carriacou Island (Grenada).; Emigration and immigration.
    - "England I Want to Go": The Effects of Migration on a Caribbean Community, 1971; RISM 17553; Hill, Donald R., 1939-; 6 pages (Box 8)
  - Carriacou Island: Folk Music (Box 8)
    - Music for the Old Parents: The Folk Religion of Carriacou as Expressed in the Big Drum Dance, 1984; RISM 18195; Hill, Donald R., 1939-; 15 pages (Box 8)
      Folk music.; Carriacou Island (Grenada).
  - Carriacou Island: Land Tenure (Box 8)
    - The Transformation of Land Rights by Transmission in Carriacou, 1956; RISM 20538; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); p. 103-138. (Box 8)
      Land tenure.; Carriacou Island (Grenada).
  - Carriacou Island: Social Life and Customs (Box 8)
    - A Note on Truth, Fact, and Tradition in Carriacou, 1971; RISM 24387; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); 15 pages (Box 8)
      Manners and customs; Carriacou Island (Grenada).
    - Kinship and Household in Carriacou, 1961; RISM 20062; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); p. 455-477. (Box 8)
- Cayman Islands (Box 8)
  - Cayman Islands: Agriculture (Box 8)
    - Shifting Cultivation in the Cayman Islands, undated; RISM 16707; Buchler, Ira R.; 9 pages (Box 8)
      Cayman Islands.; Agriculture.
  - Cayman Islands: Constitutional History (Box 8)
    - Cayman Islands: Report of the Constitutional Commissioners; Presented to Parliament by the Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs, 1991; RISM 17573; Smith, Frederick H.; 21 pages (Box 8)
      Constitutional history.; Cayman Islands.
  - Cayman Islands: Crime and Criminals (Box 8)
    - Treaty Between the United States and the United Kingdom Concerning the Cayman Islands; Relating to Mutual Legal Assistance in Criminal Matters, 1986; RISM 17791; United States. Department of State; 18 pages (Box 8)
      Cayman Islands.; Crime and criminals
  - Cayman Islands: Description and Travel (Box 8)
    - A Reporter at Large to the Miskito Bank, 1967; RISM 17460; Matthiessen, Peter; p.120-164. (Box 8)
      Cayman Islands.
    - Cayman Islands; A Sketch, 1956; RISM 17461; Doran, Edwin B., 1918-; p. 31-32, 42. (Box 8)
    - Land Forms of Grand Cayman Island, British West Indies, 1954; RISM 17462; Doran, Edwin B., 1918-; p. 360-377. (Box 8)
    - Background Notes: Cayman Islands, 1996; RISM 20616; United States. Department of State; 5/96; no content (Box 8)
    - Grand Cayman: A One-Time Pirate Island, Far at the Back of Beyond, Where it is Always Afternoon, 1928; RISM 25207; various paging (Box 8)
  - Cayman Islands: Drinking Customs (Box 8)
    - Caymanian Drinking Behavior, 1967; RISM 24071; Howe, James, 1944-; 21 pages (Box 8)
      Drinking customs.; Cayman Islands.
  - Cayman Islands: Economic Conditions (Box 8)
    - Economic Development of the Cayman Islands, 1984; RISM 17458; Cayman Islands Government Information Service; 11 pages (Box 8)
      Economic conditions.; Cayman Islands.
    - Marginal Entrepreneurship and Economic Change in the Cayman Islands, 1973; RISM 17463; Hannerz, Ulf; p. 101-111. (Box 8)
    - Cayman Islands Update, 1982; RISM 17465; Drosdik, Vincent; 2 pages (Box 8)
    - Advantages of the Cayman Islands as an Offshore Financial Centre, 1984; RISM 17541; Cayman Islands Government Information Service; 2 pages (Box 8)
    - Licensing of Banks and Trust Companies in the Cayman Islands, 1984; RISM 17542; Cayman Islands Government Information Service; 4 pages (Box 8)
      Cayman Islands.; Economic conditions.
    - Real Estate and Development in the Cayman Islands, 1984; RISM 17543; Cayman Islands Government Information Service; 14 pages (Box 8)
    - Professional, Financial, Governmental, and Retail Services in the Cayman Islands, 1984; RISM 17545; Cayman Islands Government Information Service; 9 pages (Box 8)
    - Licensing of Offshore (or Captive) Insurance Companies in the Cayman Islands, 1984; RISM 17546; Cayman Islands Government Information Service; 7 pages (Box 8)
    - Cayman Islands Currency Board; Report for the Year Ended 31st December, 1975, 1976; RISM 17547; Cayman Islands Currency Board; unpaged. (Box 8)
    - Opening a Business in the Cayman Islands, 1984; RISM 20540; Cayman Islands Government Information Service; 8 pages (Box 8)
    - Registration of Companies in the Cayman Islands, 1984; RISM 20542; Cayman Islands Government Information Service; 5 pages (Box 8)
    - The Seales Cayman Letter; An Investment, Economic and Real Estate Review of the Tax-Free Cayman Islands, 1987; RISM 23192; 14 pages (Box 8)
  - Cayman Islands: Education (Box 8)
    - Report of the Chief Education Officer, 1973; RISM 18022; Cayman Islands. Education Department; unpaged. (Box 8)
      Cayman Islands.; Education.
  - Cayman Islands: Fisheries (Box 8)
    - The Fisheries of the Cayman Islands; Report, ca. 1940; RISM 18088; Thompson, Ernest Freeman; 33 pages (Box 8)
      Cayman Islands.; Fisheries
  - Cayman Islands: Folklore (Box 8)
    - Superstitions & Sayings of the Cayman Islands, 1982; RISM 18164; 4 pages (Box 8)
      Cayman Islands.; Folklore.
  - Cayman Islands: Forests and Forestry (Box 8)
    - Forestry in the Cayman Islands; Report, 1946; RISM 18470; Swabey, Christopher; 31 pages (Box 8)
      Cayman Islands.; Forests and forestry.
  - Cayman Islands: Population (Box 8)
    - Population, Birth, Death, and Marriage Statistics of the Cayman Islands; 1986 With Some Comparative Statistics for Earlier Years, 1987; RISM 2903; 10 pages; 10.0 (Box 8)
      Statistics, Vital.; Cayman Islands.; Population.
    - Breeding in an Isolated Island Community, 1952; RISM 17459; Doran, Edwin B., 1918-; p. 263-266. (Box 8)
      Cayman Islands.; Population.
  - Cayman Islands: Postal Service (Box 8)
    - Postal Express Mail Service; Agreement Between the United States of America and the Cayman Islands, 1986; RISM 20549; United States. Department of State; 13 pages (Box 8)
      Postal service.; Cayman Islands.
  - Cayman Islands: Public Health (Box 8)
    - Medical Report, 1967: General Review of Progress, RISM 20550; 14 pages (Box 8)
      Public health.; Cayman Islands.
  - Cayman Islands: Statistics, 1991 (Box 8)
    - Statistics in Brief, 1991, 1992; RISM 17457; Cayman Islands. Statistics Office; 5 pages (Box 8)
      Statistics.; Cayman Islands.
- Central America (Box 8)
  - Central America: Antiquities (Box 8)
    - The Archeology of Costa Rica and Nicaragua, 1948; RISM 20551; Strong, William Duncan, 1899-1962; p. 121-142. (Box 8)
      Antiquities.; Central America.
    - The Archeology of Central America: An Introduction, ca. 1948; RISM 20552; Strong, William Duncan, 1899-1962; p. 69-120. (Box 8)
      Central America.; Antiquities.
  - Central America: Economic Conditions (Box 8)
    - Country Reports: Central America I and II, 1974; RISM 16321; Barclays Bank; 2 items (Box 8)
      Central America.; Economic conditions.
  - Central America: Festivals (Box 8)
    - Symbolic Dramas of Ethnic Stratification: Yucatecan Fiesta System on a Colonial Frontier, 1981; RISM 18152; Jones, Grant D., 1941-; p. 131-155. (Box 8)
      Festivals.; Central America.
  - Central America: Indians of Central America (Box 8)
    - Mapping the Distribution of Indians in Central America, 1989; RISM 20559; Davidson, William V.; p. 37-40. (Box 8)
      Indians of Central America.
    - Sociolinguistic History and the Creolist, 1981; RISM 23267; Holm, John A.; p. 40-51. (Box 8)
  - Central America: Mineral Industries (Box 8)
    - The Mineral Industry of Central American Countries, 1965 - 1974; RISM 20566; United States. Department of the Interior; 2 items; no content (Box 8)
      Mineral industries.; Central America.
  - Central America: Costa Rica, Cultural Pluralism (Box 8)
    - Pluralism and the Study of Complex Societies: Lowland Costa Rica at the Turn of the Century, 1969; RISM 17655; Olien, Michael D.; 20 pages (Box 8)
      Costa Rica.; Cultural pluralism.; Central America.
  - Central America: Costa Rica, Jamacians (Box 8)
    - Social Relations and Cultural Persistance (Or Change) Among Jamaicans in a Rural Area of Costa Rica, 1972; RISM 19087; Bozzoli de Wille, María Eugenia; p. 215-228. (Box 8)
      Central America.; Costa Rica.; Jamaicans.
  - Central America: Costa Rica, Mental Illness (Box 8)
    - The Evolvement of an Asylum into a Psychiatric Hospital: Manuel Antonio Chapui Hospital, 1972; RISM 20563; Gallegos-Chacon, Alvaro; p. 35-39. (Box 8)
      Central America.; Costa Rica.; Mental illness.
  - Central America: Guatemala, Black Carib Indians (Box 8)
    - Changes in Black Carib Kinship Terminology, 1960; RISM 16987; González, Nancie L. Solien, 1929-; p. 144-159. (Box 8)
      Central America.; Garifuna (Caribbean people).; Guatemala.
    - West Indian Characteristics of the Black Carib, 1959; RISM 16989; González, Nancie L. Solien, 1929-; p. 300-307. (Box 8)
    - Rethinking the Consanguineal Household and Matrifocality, 1984; RISM 16990; González, Nancie L. Solien, 1929-; 12 pages; p. 1-12. (Box 8)
      Guatemala.; Central America.; Garifuna (Caribbean people).